









### Kelvin Kani Sikamoi

Phone: +254708882106 | Email: sikamoikelvin777@gmail.com

**Location: Nairobi KENYA** 

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/kelvin-sikamoi-9574aa230

### **SUMMARY**

- 1+ years of experience in Information Technology Networks and Cloud Services
- Expertise in Azure Compute, Networking, Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery solutions
- Customer-facing experience with different computer, networking.
- Skilled in infrastructure implementation in Azure and migration from on-prem to Azure
- Hands on experience configuring Cisco networks.
- Member Toastmasters International
- Securing networks.
- Aspiring Cloud /Network Solutions Architect

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a dependable and solutions-focused individual wanting to contribute my cloud computing, cybersecurity and computer networking expertise to a developing company and vibrant team.

Highly motivated, with a growth-oriented learning mindset, consistently behaving as a team member to accomplish goals and complete duties as requested and permitted, but also being equally effective at working well alone with little to no supervision.

I always try to stay current.

#### **SKILLS**

### **Technologies**

**Cloud:** Backup and Disaster Recovery, Data and File storage, Azure Migrate, Azure File Sync, Azure Update Management, Virtual Networks and Azure Networking, Azure Active Directory.

**System Administration:** Configuring and Troubleshooting Active Directory and Group Policy Objects, Microsoft Teams, SharePoint, and Azure Active Directory

Routing/WAN: Route Distribution, IPv4 and IPv6 Routing Switching: LAN, Configuring routers, access point.

Cyber Security: CISCO cybersecurity.

Application Delivery: Management of existing application delivery services, Troubleshooting of basic connectivity Issues

Mounting Devices: Designing racks, Cabling management, Office computer and computer Labs setups.

















## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Major Projects Undertaken**

- Transferring office on-prem data to azure cloud creating virtual machines, creating azure storages and configuring Active Directory. Also transferring their website to host their front end and back end in the Azure cloud.
- Been able to set up a full government computer lab running on an on-prem server with a capacity of 20 students, mounting of the server rack, cabling of ethernet cables to each PC.

## **Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission**

## **Chief Information Technology Officer**

S May – August 2022

- Configuring KIEMS election kits.
- Configuring Thuraya network Satellites.
- Managing hired personal data and ensuring security of data.

## Resource Cloud Academy (RCA)

Feb 2022 - Present

#### Mentor

- Empowering students in tech to be able to start upskilling in different areas of Technology.
- Learning more of cloud
- Getting mentorship from Techies who have experience in the industry.

### **Gaichu Managed Services**

Feb 2023 – Present

- Responsive technical support service •Confirm that the SLA-set client service availability is met. Diagnose customer service issues and make recommendations. Put effective solutions in place.
- Investigate and generate thorough Fault Reports describing client link failure problems. •Take preventive action keep ace up to stop/reduce/stop errors from happening. Making sure the Company CDI is attained
- Installing and configuring computer hardware is a WAN/LAN Managed Services expert's specialty. Systems and programs for operating systems: keeping an eye on and maintaining computer systems Guiding staff or clients through a sequence of steps over the phone or in person can assist set up systems or fix problems.
- Diagnosing and fixing hardware/software issues, as well as troubleshooting system and network issues; changing components as necessary.
- Fix a problem or set up a system: \*assisting with the introduction of new applications.

















Aug 2021 – Present

## **EDUCATION**

# Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Kenya

Bachelor of Science – BSc Computer Technology

**Mckinsey Academy** 

Leadership and Problem-solving

Nov 2022 - Present

**Nyahururu Elite Senior School** 

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Jan 2014 - Nov 2017

KCSE Grade: B-

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals.

Microsoft Security, Compliance and Identity Fundamentals.

Networking Essentials.

Cisco Certified Network Associate (Ongoing)

Ethical hacking Essential

**IBM Cloud Essentials** 

Cyber Threat Management

IBM Cybersecurity Fundamentals

Introduction to IOT

NSE 1 Network Security Associate

NSE 2 Network Security Associate

NSE 3 Network Security Associate

\_\_\_\_\_





